Guide to the Wayne P. Ellis Collection of Kodakiana, 1886-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photography Manuals Series, [circa 1890]-1987 and undated (Box 57)
  - Trade and Technical Subseries(some non-Kodak) 1917-1980 and undated (Box 75)
    - Contents of Box: (Box 79)
      - Photomicrography of Metals, 1971 (Box 79)
      - Basic Scientific Photography, 1973 (Box 79)
      - Photography in ..., 1954, (4 items) (Box 79)
      - Photographic Surveillance Techniques for Law Enforcement Agencies, 1972 (Box 79)
      - High-Speed Photography in Product Development, 1955 (Box 79)
      - Kodak Plates for Scientific and Technical Applications, 1968 (Box 79)
      - Expand Applications of High Speed Photography, 1955 (Box 79)
      - Incidental Intelligence About Kodak Resists, 1968, 1969 (Box 79)
      - Promotional Programs for the Professional Studio, 1966 (Box 79)
- Kodak Sales/Dealer Manuals Series, 1910s-1956 and undated (Box 79)
  Training materials for sales personnel and Kodak dealers. Arranged in chronological order within folders.
  - Contents of Box: (Box 80)
    - Sales/dealer manuals, [191-]-[194-], (7 items) (Box 80)
    - Promotional materials and catalogs for dealers, [194-]-[195-], (10 items) (Box 80)
    - Eastman Photographic Course for Salesmen, 1938-1944, (3 folders) (Box 80)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 81)
    - Conference notes from Kodak photographic sales training, 1956 (Box 81)
    - Loose materials from notebook above, 1956 (Box 81)
    - Eastman Reference Manual for Salesmen, [1937?]-[1941?] (Box 81)
- Other Kodak-Related Publications Series, 1888-1983 and undated (Box 81)
  Chiefly ephemeral non-serial publications related to Kodak products, company history, or photographic activities sponsored by Kodak. The novels listed were acquired by Mr. Ellis in order to document the unauthorized use of the Kodak trade name. Arranged in original order.
  - Contents of Box: (Box 82)
    - Proceedings of the Golden Anniversary Convention of the Photographers Association of America, 1930 (Box 82)
    - Stereo Photography in Rochester NY up to 1900, 1975 (Box 82)
    - The Gospel Kodak Abroad (novel), 1893 (Box 82)
    - Down in Porto Rico With a Kodak (novel), 1898 (Box 82)
    - Captain Kodak (novel), 1899 (Box 82)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 83)
    - Publicités Kodak, 1910-1939, 1983 (Box 83)
    - Invoices, 1910 (Box 83)
    - Classroom Projects Using Photography, 1975 (Box 83)
      - Part 1 - Elementary (Box 83)
      - Part 2 - Secondary (Box 83)
    - Hawk Eye Club Awards programs (25-year Kodak service club), 1952-1953 (Box 83)
      Includes handwritten manuscript of presentation speech by President J. Kowalski.
    - Kodak Park 50 Years Ago: A Boy's Eye View of 1904, [1954?] (Box 83)
    - 20 Years of the Kodak Camera Club of Rochester, 1940 (Box 83)
    - Program from Army-Navy Production award presentation, 1942 (Box 83)
    - The American Boy Photographer, undated (Box 83)
    - Photographic Mosaics: An Annual Record of Photographic Progress, 1888 (Box 83)
- Marketing Samples and Promotional Materials Series, [189-?]-[198-?] and undated (Box 83)
  Wide variety of Kodak artifacts such as samples books, albums, and promotional novelties. Arranged in original order.
  - Contents of Box: (Box 84)
    - Velox books (sample black and white photographs), undated, (3 items) (Box 84)
    - Photographic paper samples book, 1953 (Box 84)
    - Kodak Portfolio: Sample black and white photographs from exhibition, 1897 (Box 84)
    - Album of Dekko prints ( black and white photographs shot with various Kodak cameras), [189-] (Box 84)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 85)
    - Kodak photo albums, [circa 1939], [195-], and undated, (4 items) (Box 85)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 86)
    - Negative book, 1929 (Box 86)
    - Empty photo album, undated (Box 86)
    - Empty negative book, undated (Box 86)
    - Photo album, 1902 (Box 86)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 87)
    - Sample packaging/film processing envelopes, photos printed as promotional materials, [189?]-[192?], (76 items) (Box 87)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 88)
    - Novelties (Box 88)
      Wide variety of Kodak promotional materials used as giveaways and for in-store use. Almost all have no date, but most are 20th century artifacts.
      - Stuffed kangaroo with Pocket Kodak in pouch (Box 88)
      - Counter mat (Box 88)
      - Pocket Instamatic matchboxes, various matchbooks (Box 88)
      - Kodak "facts" playing cards (Box 88)
      - Negative pencil, Kodak pen (Box 88)
      - Kodaslide noise-making postcard (Box 88)
      - Kodak Park postcard (Box 88)
      - "Photographic oracle" (Box 88)
      - Processing/calendar cards (Box 88)
      - Kalart sunlight guide for taking pictures (Box 88)
      - Ads/instructions for Kodak Bank (Box 88)
      - Pocket coin bank (Box 88)
      - Kodak coin (Box 88)
      - Instamatic mini-notebook (Box 88)
      - "Filmsbee" (frisbee with film) (Box 88)
      - Magnifying glass (Box 88)
      - 65th anniversary buttons (Box 88)
      - Kodak pin (Box 88)
      - French calendar, 1973 (Box 88)
      - French paperweight (Box 88)
      - "German Schnapps Novelty" (for New Year's?) (Box 88)
      - Kodak T-shirt (Box 88)
      - Calendar holder (Box 88)
      - Kodak medal (Box 88)
      - Kodak lighter (Box 88)
      - Kodak keychains (Box 88)
      - Kodak puzzle pieces (Box 88)
      - Filter test chart (Box 88)
      - Ma-Time Computer (Box 88)
      - Kodak Banner (Box 88)
      - Kodak reflector (Box 88)
      - "Brownies in Stock!" stamp (Box 88)
- Oversize Materials, circa 1918-1988 and undated (Box 88)
  Chiefly photographs used by Kodak for promotional campaigns, but also includes counter signs and some company history materials, including employee photographs.
  - Contents of Box: (Box 89)
    - Promotional materials, 1931-1978 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 89)
      Includes advertisement samples, sample scripts for demos, and some foreign advertising materials.
  - Contents of Box: (Box 90)
    - Framed black and white photograph - "No. 4 Panorama," undated (Box 90)
    - Unframed black and white photographs - includes Kodak girl, Velox display, undated (Box 90)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 91)
    - Framed photograph - Kodak girl, undated (Box 91)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 92)
    - Promotional materials, store-printed, ca. 1920, (22 items) (Box 92)
  - Contents of Box: (Box 93)
    - Kodak employee photographs, circa 1918-ca. 1924, (3 items) (Box 93)
    - Biographical information about George Eastman, 1954, 1976, 1988, (3 items) (Box 93)
  - Early Kodak advertisements scrapbook 1, 1880s-1912 (Box 94)
    [Contents digitized in the Emergence of Advertising in America online collection, numbers K0525-K0565.]
  - Early Kodak advertisements scrapbook 1, 1905-1919 (Box 95)
    [Contents digitized in the Emergence of Advertising in America online collection, numbers K0566-K0579.]